A lot of companies now,
they are interested in data analytics.
And they have data scientists,
and they've invested a lot.
And That's a really
important field,
but there was only one
problem with it. And that is
often in data analytics,
we have to actually
rely on existing data.
Now, here's sort of a set
of issues that we typically run
into, and that's why we
need experimentation.
First of all, when it
comes to innovation,
we often don't have the data
because if the data was already there,
it wouldn't be very
innovative because someone has already
done it before, so it's
not innovative. So by definition,
innovation means that we
usually don't have the data to
analyze to begin with. Second
of all, context matters.
Just because something works
in one sort of area, doesn't
mean that it works in another
area. And then finally,
when we do data analytics,
we usually get correlations.
You know, that is
variables correlate with each other.
But correlations
is not the same as causation.
The most fundamental question
that we need to know as
managers is whether an
action that we want to take,
a management action or
decision actually causes some outcome
that we sort of aspire
to. The only surefire way
of actually addressing
causality is to run rigorous
controlled experiments.
So if you have a data
analytics program and you're just relying
on existing data, you're
you're you're not there yet.
What you have to do is
you actually have to add experimentation
to your toolbox as well,
and the two will actually augment
each other. Yep. So that's
what it's all about.